<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: A More Progressive Tax System Makes People Happier</title>
	<atom:link href="/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/</link>
	<description>A better world through data.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Edward</title>
		<link>/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/#comment-62999</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Edward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 04:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=249#comment-62999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I used to be a very big supporter of the progressive income tax, but now I have come to realize there is only one tax that is progressive: a tax on land values.

Taxes on income merely reduce production. Of course in a very corrupt system in which most gains in production are siphoned off by concentrated power-holders, less production means more equality... though equality and prosperity need not be mutually exclusive. It is a false choice.

I have heard arguments that it creates incentive for businesses to hire people in order to deduct taxes, but that is a dubious claim at best. If I were wrong about this, I&#039;d be glad to know, but I remain entirely unconvinced.

What created the post-war middle class in the US was artificial labor scarcities, like overtime laws, child labor laws, and so on. These boosted the relative market power for all laborers. You could even say cartelized them. 

Keynesians like Galbraith minced no words about that objective. They wanted to create &quot;countervailing powers&quot; to balance out the influence of corporations and industrial consortiums. They saw the role of unions as primarily relevant in a political manner, and their apolitical collective bargaining schemes were relatively pointless (I&#039;d argue harmful).

Then people like Ralph Nader moved to mobilize consumers as another column in the system of countervailing powers.

However the balance of power has been eroded over the past three decades, and now there is merely one organize political interest group with any clout anymore. I bet you can guess which.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to be a very big supporter of the progressive income tax, but now I have come to realize there is only one tax that is progressive: a tax on land values.</p>
<p>Taxes on income merely reduce production. Of course in a very corrupt system in which most gains in production are siphoned off by concentrated power-holders, less production means more equality&#8230; though equality and prosperity need not be mutually exclusive. It is a false choice.</p>
<p>I have heard arguments that it creates incentive for businesses to hire people in order to deduct taxes, but that is a dubious claim at best. If I were wrong about this, I&#8217;d be glad to know, but I remain entirely unconvinced.</p>
<p>What created the post-war middle class in the US was artificial labor scarcities, like overtime laws, child labor laws, and so on. These boosted the relative market power for all laborers. You could even say cartelized them. </p>
<p>Keynesians like Galbraith minced no words about that objective. They wanted to create &#8220;countervailing powers&#8221; to balance out the influence of corporations and industrial consortiums. They saw the role of unions as primarily relevant in a political manner, and their apolitical collective bargaining schemes were relatively pointless (I&#8217;d argue harmful).</p>
<p>Then people like Ralph Nader moved to mobilize consumers as another column in the system of countervailing powers.</p>
<p>However the balance of power has been eroded over the past three decades, and now there is merely one organize political interest group with any clout anymore. I bet you can guess which.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
