<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Taxes &#8211; Think by Numbers</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/taxes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A better world through data.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 15:30:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i2.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-Think-By-Numbers-tbn-logo-favicon-icon-Thumbnail-600-x-600-transparent.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Taxes &#8211; Think by Numbers</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">26068032</site>	<item>
		<title>A More Progressive Tax System Makes People Happier</title>
		<link>/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/</link>
		<comments>/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 22:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Taxes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flat tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government Spending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progressive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[standard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax system]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=249</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A new study comparing 54 nations found that the more progressive the tax policy is, the happier the citizens are.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/">A More Progressive Tax System Makes People Happier</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Think by Numbers</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_519" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img data-attachment-id="519" data-permalink="/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/attachment/smileymoneyface/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?fit=190%2C190&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="190,190" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Smiley Money Face" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Smiley Money Face&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?fit=190%2C190&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?fit=190%2C190&amp;ssl=1" class="size-full wp-image-519 " title="Smiley Money Face" src="https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?resize=190%2C190" alt="Smiley Money Face" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?w=190&amp;ssl=1 190w, https://i0.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/SmileyMoneyFace.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 190px) 100vw, 190px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Illustration by The New York Times</p></div>
<p>From medicalnewstoday.com:</p>
<p>The way some people talk, you&#8217;d think that a flat tax system &#8211; in which everyone pays at the same rate regardless of income &#8211; would make citizens feel better than more progressive taxation, where wealthier people are taxed at higher rates. Indeed, the U.S. has been diminishing progressivity of its tax structure for decades.</p>
<p>But a new study comparing 54 nations found that flattening the tax risks flattening social wellbeing as well. &#8220;The more progressive the tax policy is, the happier the citizens are,&#8221; says University of Virginia psychologist Shigehiro Oishi, summarizing the findings, which will be published in an upcoming issue of Psychological Science, a journal of the Association for Psychological Science. Oishi conducted the study with Ulrich Schimmack of the University of Toronto at Mississauga and Ed Diener, also at University of Illinois and the Gallup Organization.</p>
<p>The researchers analyzed the relationship between tax progressivity and personal well-being in 54 nations surveyed by the Gallup Organization in 2007 &#8211; a total of <a href="http://www.sharing.org/information-centre/reports/financing-global-sharing-economy-part-three-1-taxing-financial">59,634 </a>respondents. Well-being was expressed in people&#8217;s assessments of their overall life quality, from &#8220;worst&#8221; to &#8220;best possible life,&#8221; on a scale of 1 to 10; and in whether they enjoyed positive daily experiences (such as smiling, being treated with respect, and eating good food) or suffered negative ones, including sadness, worry, and shame. Finally, the analysis looked at the participants&#8217; satisfaction with their nation&#8217;s public goods, from schools to clean air.</p>
<p>The degree of progressivity was measured by the difference between the highest and lowest tax rates, corrected for such confounding factors as family size, social security taxes paid, and tax benefits received by individuals.</p>
<p>The results: On average, residents of the nations with the most progressive taxation evaluated their own lives as closer to &#8220;the best possible.&#8221; They also reported having more satisfying experiences and fewer discomfiting ones than respondents living in nations with less progressive taxes. That happiness, Oishi says, was &#8220;explained by a greater degree of satisfaction with the public goods, such as housing, education, and public transportation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Higher government spending per se did not yield greater happiness, in spite of the well-being that was associated with satisfaction with state-funded services. In fact, there was a slight negative correlation between government spending and average happiness.</p>
<p>&#8220;That data is kind of weird,&#8221; Oishi says. He guesses that the misalignment might indicate national differences in the efficiency with which those services are delivered or in people&#8217;s relative ability to access them. For example, the U.S. spends more on education and health care than other developed countries, &#8220;but its international standing in those areas is not so great.&#8221; Such puzzling findings may be illuminated in further research.</p>
<p>The study, like others Oishi has done looking at connections between economics and personal life, has important social implications. &#8220;If the goal of societies is to make citizens happy, tax policy matters,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Certain policies, like tax progressivity, seem to be more conducive to the happiness of the people.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/releases/234017.php">http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/releases/234017.php</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/">A More Progressive Tax System Makes People Happier</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Think by Numbers</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taxes/a-more-progressive-tax-system-makes-people-happier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://media.blubrry.com/thinkbynumbers/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/tbn011_taxes_make_us_happy.mp3" length="5242880" type="audio/mpeg" />
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">249</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Debt Will Swell Under Top GOP Hopefuls’ Tax Plans</title>
		<link>/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/</link>
		<comments>/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 18:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taxes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candidates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiscal conservative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiscal liberal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gingrich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santorum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax policies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=1818</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The national debt would balloon under tax policies championed by three of the four major Republican candidates for president, according to an independent analysis of tax and spending proposals so far offered by the campaigns. The lone exception is Texas Rep. Ron Paul, who would pair a big reduction in tax rates with even bigger cuts in government services, slicing about $2 trillion from [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/">Debt Will Swell Under Top GOP Hopefuls’ Tax Plans</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Think by Numbers</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/running-in-the-red-how-the-us-on-the-road-to-surplus-detoured-to-massive-debt/2011/04/28/AFFU7rNF_story.html">national debt would</a> balloon under <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/romney-obama-release-dueling-tax-overhaul-proposals/2012/02/22/gIQAKOLrTR_story.html">tax policies</a> championed by three of the four major Republican candidates for president, according to an independent analysis of tax and spending proposals so far offered by the campaigns.</p>
<div id="article">
<div id="article_body">
<div>
<article>The lone exception is Texas Rep. Ron Paul, who would pair a big reduction in tax rates with even bigger cuts in government services, slicing about $2 trillion from future borrowing.</article>
</div>
<div id="article-side-rail">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>According to the report released Thursday by U.S. Budget Watch, a project of the bipartisan Committee for a Responsible Federal Budget, former Pennsylvania senator Rick Santorum and former House speaker Newt Gingrich would do the most damage to the nation’s finances, offering tax and spending policies likely to require trillions of dollars in fresh borrowing.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="1828" data-permalink="/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/attachment/debt-by-gop-presidential-candidate-2012/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?fit=707%2C407&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="707,407" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="debt by GOP presidential candidate 2012" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;The national debt would balloon under tax policies championed by three of the four major Republican candidates for president, according to an independent analysis of tax and spending proposals so far offered by the campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lone exception is Texas Rep. Ron Paul, who would pair a big reduction in tax rates with even bigger cuts in government services, slicing about $2 trillion from future borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?fit=300%2C173&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?fit=707%2C407&amp;ssl=1" class="aligncenter  wp-image-1828" title="Debt by GOP Presidential Candidates 2012" src="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?resize=636%2C366" alt="Graph of Total Debt by GOP Presidential Candidates 2012" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?w=707&amp;ssl=1 707w, https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?resize=300%2C173&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/thinkbynumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/debt-by-GOP-presidential-candidate-2012.jpg?resize=672%2C387&amp;ssl=1 672w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Graph Source: <a href="http://crfb.org/">http://crfb.org/</a></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<article>Both men have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/mitt-romney-tax-returns-make-him-a-personal-embodiment-of-gop-tax-policy/2012/01/24/gIQANvsoOQ_story.html">proposed to sharply cut taxes </a>but have not identified spending cuts sufficient to make up for the lost cash, the report said. By 2021, the debt would rise by about $4.5 trillion under Santorum’s policies and by about $7 trillion under Gingrich’s plan, pushing the portion of the debt held by outside investors to well over 100 percent of the overall economy, the study said.The red ink would gush a little more slowly under former Massachusetts governor Mitt Romney, the report said. Until this week, Romney had paired $1.35 trillion in tax cuts with $1.2 trillion in spending reductions, leaving the debt rising on a trajectory that closely tracks current policies.But that changed Wednesday, when Romney proposed to cut federal income tax rates by 20 percent more for all earners, which would slash U.S. revenue by more than $2 trillion over 10 years.Romney economic adviser Glenn Hubbard said the lost cash would be recovered by closing tax loopholes and boosting economic activity. But until the campaign offers a more specific plan, Budget Watch analysts said Romney’s entire framework would add about $2.6 trillion to the debt by 2021.Only Paul emerged as a fiscal conservative in the report. His policies would cut tax revenue by more than $5 trillion over the next decade, the report said, but the loss would be offset by more than $7 trillion in spending cuts, including deep reductions in defense and federal health programs.The report marks the first independent attempt to gauge the overall impact of policies proposed by the GOP candidates on the nation’s $15.4 trillion debt.“As we enter the thick of the campaign season, no one can ignore the debt issue,” said Maya MacGuineas, president of the Committee for a Responsible Federal Budget, which supports debt-reduction efforts in Washington. “This report is designed to inform the public on the fiscal policies put forward by each of the Republican candidates and stimulate debate on this crucial topic.”Paul campaign spokesman Gary Howard welcomed the analysis. “It’s not a surprise to us the report found that Congressman Paul’s plan is the only one that doesn’t raise the debt,” Howard said via e-mail. “The critical importance of dealing with our growing debt has been a hallmark issue of Dr. Paul’s campaign and his career.”</p>
<p>Romney spokesperson Andrea Saul declined to directly address the findings, arguing that Romney is the only candidate to lay out a realistic budget framework “that will jump-start the American economy and bring tax relief to middle-income Americans.”</p>
<p>Aides to Santorum and Gingrich did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>The report does not include an analysis of President Obama’s latest spending blueprint, which seeks to reduce borrowing by $3 trillion by 2021. Budget Watch plans to analyze Obama’s request in future reports.</p>
<p>The report does not seek to offer support to any candidate, and its authors have gone to significant lengths to give the campaigns and their developing policy ideas the benefit of the doubt. The report offers three scenarios for each candidate: A “low-debt scenario” is based on the most generous assumptions about the ability of proposals to save money or generate revenue. A “high-debt scenario” is much more stringent.</p>
<p>The numbers cited above are taken from the report’s “intermediate-debt scenario.” which “gives credit for non-specified changes to certain parts of the budget,” such as promises to reduce some forms of spending by a certain percentage, even if the candidate has yet to nail down ways of generating the cash.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lori-montgomery/2011/03/04/ABffwuN_page.html" rel="author">Lori Montgomery</a>, Published: February 23 <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/report-debt-will-swell-under-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/2012/02/22/gIQAzAJvUR_story.html?wpisrc=dailypaul" target="_blank">The Washington Post</a></p>
</article>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/">Debt Will Swell Under Top GOP Hopefuls’ Tax Plans</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Think by Numbers</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/debt/debt-swell-top-gop-hopefuls-tax-plans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1818</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
