<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Why Think by Numbers?</title>
	<atom:link href="/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A better world through data.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: CmdrR</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-63111</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CmdrR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-63111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Numbers and facts indeed do not lie... in the same way that guns do not kill people. However, numbers and facts do show up in a lot of misinformation in the same way that guns have an absolute affinity for showing up at murders. While I don&#039;t dismiss any of these articles, I would strongly appreciate sourcing on all things.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Numbers and facts indeed do not lie&#8230; in the same way that guns do not kill people. However, numbers and facts do show up in a lot of misinformation in the same way that guns have an absolute affinity for showing up at murders. While I don&#8217;t dismiss any of these articles, I would strongly appreciate sourcing on all things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike P. Sinn</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-63110</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-63110</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lots of great points!  Thanks! :D]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lots of great points!  Thanks! 😀</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Yes Free</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-63109</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yes Free]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-63109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nice explanation of how the brain works.. But I think The combination of the Triune Brains makes a human supreme over other humans... For one can use their stem and limbic system after accessing rational data like numbers and stats.... A powerful Media is one that uses rational thought to influence limbuc system and brain stem... Because you can have a lot of data but refuse to put that data into action for a limbic system reason or belief. 

For example Human poachers kill animals not just because of brain stem flight and fight or survival but for Economics i. e. selling ivory for profit to obtain capital to build your utopia. 

Biological Warfare is the use of rational understanding of diseases to fight unwanted species or animals, whose destruction has an effect on Economics. 


Thus the most powerful human is one who unifies his three brains into one brain. The problem of power is that it supercedes good and evil, truth and falsehood]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nice explanation of how the brain works.. But I think The combination of the Triune Brains makes a human supreme over other humans&#8230; For one can use their stem and limbic system after accessing rational data like numbers and stats&#8230;. A powerful Media is one that uses rational thought to influence limbuc system and brain stem&#8230; Because you can have a lot of data but refuse to put that data into action for a limbic system reason or belief. </p>
<p>For example Human poachers kill animals not just because of brain stem flight and fight or survival but for Economics i. e. selling ivory for profit to obtain capital to build your utopia. </p>
<p>Biological Warfare is the use of rational understanding of diseases to fight unwanted species or animals, whose destruction has an effect on Economics. </p>
<p>Thus the most powerful human is one who unifies his three brains into one brain. The problem of power is that it supercedes good and evil, truth and falsehood</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Growing Poverty in America &#124; So Sue me</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-54528</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Growing Poverty in America &#124; So Sue me]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 16:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-54528</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Why Think by Numbers? [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Why Think by Numbers? [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Election Year Politics – Hold on to your Limbic System! &#124; Clare Consultation</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-34449</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Election Year Politics – Hold on to your Limbic System! &#124; Clare Consultation]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 21:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-34449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] In fact, given time, encouragement and opportunity – and especially given numbers, says blogger Mike Sinn – our frontal lobes kick right on line and rev up to make more integrated decisions – feelings [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] In fact, given time, encouragement and opportunity – and especially given numbers, says blogger Mike Sinn – our frontal lobes kick right on line and rev up to make more integrated decisions – feelings [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike P. Sinn</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-30876</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-30876</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks, Lisa!  Please let me know if you have any ideas how we can do that!  My email is m@thinkbynumbers.org.  Unfortunately, we&#039;ve given them about 10,000 nuclear bombs, I think.  I&#039;ve been wanting to make a post on how many times we could kill everyone on earth with our current nuclear stockpile. But I just haven&#039;t had the time yet.  


What do you do for a living?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks, Lisa!  Please let me know if you have any ideas how we can do that!  My email is <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;to:&#x6d;&#x40;&#x74;&#x68;&#105;nkb&#x79;&#x6e;&#x75;&#109;&#98;ers&#x2e;&#x6f;&#x72;&#103;">&#109;&#64;&#x74;h&#x69;n&#x6b;b&#x79;n&#x75;m&#x62;&#101;&#x72;&#115;.&#111;r&#x67;</a>.  Unfortunately, we&#8217;ve given them about 10,000 nuclear bombs, I think.  I&#8217;ve been wanting to make a post on how many times we could kill everyone on earth with our current nuclear stockpile. But I just haven&#8217;t had the time yet.  </p>
<p>What do you do for a living?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Lisa Gunther</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-30874</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Gunther]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-30874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am so glad I&#039;m not the only one who thinks like this - for a looonnnggg time, I believed that I was totally alone in my thoughts on politics and economics.  It&#039;s really nice to hear someone lay out my thoughts in a clear and concise way.  Now, if we could just get the psychopaths out of office, I believe we could make some real progress in this country.  Alas, we have given the nuclear bomb to a newborn.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am so glad I&#8217;m not the only one who thinks like this &#8211; for a looonnnggg time, I believed that I was totally alone in my thoughts on politics and economics.  It&#8217;s really nice to hear someone lay out my thoughts in a clear and concise way.  Now, if we could just get the psychopaths out of office, I believe we could make some real progress in this country.  Alas, we have given the nuclear bomb to a newborn.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Gigi Jacobs</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-28449</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gigi Jacobs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 06:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-28449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Devilis, how appropriate. It was not my fathers misinformation on what a Republican was, but rather the reading of the two platforms that made my decision solid. I guess you haven&#039;t read it yet. And if you don&#039;t know this about numbers, it takes a great deal of integrity to use them honestly and with the right weighing to give them correct meaning. For instance your clue about being in a a Republican State and then a Democratic State says little about anything for you&#039;ve not included the numbers and where they began and stopped to have any meaning what so ever so you basically made a nonsensical statement. And I will call out my father for he is the typical Republican statistically (the majority) and he does behave as the majority behave and so it was not his teaching but my reading which led me to believe that Republicans are for all the things that I am not. 

Like safety nets for the poor, Medicare, Social Security, a high enough corporate tax so after deductions and subsidies they don&#039;t pay 11% but pay 30% or more like the rest of us, rules and regulations so they don&#039;t cheat and pollute and kill the people who work for them with their poisonous chemicals, less tort reform for if anyone knows about the law, then they know that tort reform is built into the law and the only reason to make laws to &quot;reform&quot; is to take away a person&#039;s right to sue for the total of what he has lost, social programs like welfare and Food Stamps (surely 3% won&#039;t kill you while you give up 50% of every dollar in corporate welfare), infrastructure so our bridges don&#039;t fall into the rivers after the corporate tankers run them into the water, a fair and just minimum wage (you know like 3 times what it used to be when I had employees for who would be so cheap to take all the winnings and pay the workers nothing, Rules on health insurance companies when they get so out of hand that they pay themselves all the premium checks and have nothing left for the injured, and I could go on with 50 or more different things between a Republican and a Democrat but I&#039;d rather not for the things a Republican loves are the things that make me hate being around selfish and egotistical humans when there is so much pain our there that could be really fixed if one did the numbers on all and did the honestly.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Devilis, how appropriate. It was not my fathers misinformation on what a Republican was, but rather the reading of the two platforms that made my decision solid. I guess you haven&#8217;t read it yet. And if you don&#8217;t know this about numbers, it takes a great deal of integrity to use them honestly and with the right weighing to give them correct meaning. For instance your clue about being in a a Republican State and then a Democratic State says little about anything for you&#8217;ve not included the numbers and where they began and stopped to have any meaning what so ever so you basically made a nonsensical statement. And I will call out my father for he is the typical Republican statistically (the majority) and he does behave as the majority behave and so it was not his teaching but my reading which led me to believe that Republicans are for all the things that I am not. </p>
<p>Like safety nets for the poor, Medicare, Social Security, a high enough corporate tax so after deductions and subsidies they don&#8217;t pay 11% but pay 30% or more like the rest of us, rules and regulations so they don&#8217;t cheat and pollute and kill the people who work for them with their poisonous chemicals, less tort reform for if anyone knows about the law, then they know that tort reform is built into the law and the only reason to make laws to &#8220;reform&#8221; is to take away a person&#8217;s right to sue for the total of what he has lost, social programs like welfare and Food Stamps (surely 3% won&#8217;t kill you while you give up 50% of every dollar in corporate welfare), infrastructure so our bridges don&#8217;t fall into the rivers after the corporate tankers run them into the water, a fair and just minimum wage (you know like 3 times what it used to be when I had employees for who would be so cheap to take all the winnings and pay the workers nothing, Rules on health insurance companies when they get so out of hand that they pay themselves all the premium checks and have nothing left for the injured, and I could go on with 50 or more different things between a Republican and a Democrat but I&#8217;d rather not for the things a Republican loves are the things that make me hate being around selfish and egotistical humans when there is so much pain our there that could be really fixed if one did the numbers on all and did the honestly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Devils Advocate</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-28388</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devils Advocate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 11:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-28388</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gigi,
I am truly sorry for what your father did to you but..... Please do not list him as a republican then go on to say what he &quot;indulged in&quot;. It is that kind of backasswards grouping and hating that divides groups. Coming from a state that had the lowest unemployment, highest budget surplus, one of the lowest crimes, highest collegiate research, one of the happiest states in the U.S., and is predominantly run under conservative values and republican legislation (North Dakota) while being raised until I was 18 in a democratic state which cannot say the same for unemployment and budget (MInnesota) I would say if you opened your mind and do not let what political stance your father had bias your thinking, you would find that conservatives (ie. republicans) are not that far off from liberals (democrats). It is people making this rash distinction based on what they are brought up to think that makes this country divided on every issue without really understanding the issues.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gigi,<br />
I am truly sorry for what your father did to you but&#8230;.. Please do not list him as a republican then go on to say what he &#8220;indulged in&#8221;. It is that kind of backasswards grouping and hating that divides groups. Coming from a state that had the lowest unemployment, highest budget surplus, one of the lowest crimes, highest collegiate research, one of the happiest states in the U.S., and is predominantly run under conservative values and republican legislation (North Dakota) while being raised until I was 18 in a democratic state which cannot say the same for unemployment and budget (MInnesota) I would say if you opened your mind and do not let what political stance your father had bias your thinking, you would find that conservatives (ie. republicans) are not that far off from liberals (democrats). It is people making this rash distinction based on what they are brought up to think that makes this country divided on every issue without really understanding the issues.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Gigi Jacobs</title>
		<link>/statistical-cost-benefit-analysis-vs-irrational-emotion/#comment-28009</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gigi Jacobs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?page_id=217#comment-28009</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think the world just may be better off with the two of us! 

Thank you for your kind comment and may our lives get better and better with each experience we have the privilege of having! 

Best to you dearest Mike, 

Gigi Jacobs]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think the world just may be better off with the two of us! </p>
<p>Thank you for your kind comment and may our lives get better and better with each experience we have the privilege of having! </p>
<p>Best to you dearest Mike, </p>
<p>Gigi Jacobs</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
