<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Obama to cut deficit in half&#8230; After quadrupling it.</title>
	<atom:link href="/uncategorized/obama-to-cut-deficit-in-half-after/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/uncategorized/obama-to-cut-deficit-in-half-after/</link>
	<description>A better world through data.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike P. Sinn</title>
		<link>/uncategorized/obama-to-cut-deficit-in-half-after/#comment-62792</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 03:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/wordpress/?p=8#comment-62792</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Interesting point!  Thanks for commenting.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I agree that increases in mandatory spending have a great deal to do with the deficit.  However, social security and medicare demographics can&#039;t explain a deficit quadrupling in one year and the getting cut in half the next year.  It&#039;s just silly that Obama&#039;s acting like creating a deficit double Bush&#039;s worst deficit is some kind of accomplishment.  It&#039;s not like Bush was known for his deficit hawkishness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama could have vetoed enough spending to prevent a quadrupling.  Discretionary examples include the $787 billion  American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 comprised 40% of the deficit that year.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The $150 billion Obama&#039;s spent on wars in 2009 comprised about 8% of the deficit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama spent $90 billion on other corporate welfare in 2009. Another 5%.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting point!  Thanks for commenting.  </p>
<p>I agree that increases in mandatory spending have a great deal to do with the deficit.  However, social security and medicare demographics can&#39;t explain a deficit quadrupling in one year and the getting cut in half the next year.  It&#39;s just silly that Obama&#39;s acting like creating a deficit double Bush&#39;s worst deficit is some kind of accomplishment.  It&#39;s not like Bush was known for his deficit hawkishness.</p>
<p>Obama could have vetoed enough spending to prevent a quadrupling.  Discretionary examples include the $787 billion  American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 comprised 40% of the deficit that year.  </p>
<p>The $150 billion Obama&#39;s spent on wars in 2009 comprised about 8% of the deficit.</p>
<p>Obama spent $90 billion on other corporate welfare in 2009. Another 5%.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Anonymous</title>
		<link>/uncategorized/obama-to-cut-deficit-in-half-after/#comment-62791</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/wordpress/?p=8#comment-62791</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What you&#039;re failing to recognize is that the first two years of budgeting under Obama involve a rise in fixed costs to the government (social security/ unemployment/ medicade/ military expenditures) that pushes the deficit up independent of any budgeting decisions.  Don&#039;t make the problem worse by underreporting the obvious.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What you&#39;re failing to recognize is that the first two years of budgeting under Obama involve a rise in fixed costs to the government (social security/ unemployment/ medicade/ military expenditures) that pushes the deficit up independent of any budgeting decisions.  Don&#39;t make the problem worse by underreporting the obvious.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
