<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Governments Spend $1.8 Trillion Murdering Us and Destroying Our Property Annually</title>
	<atom:link href="/military/military-spending/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/military/military-spending/</link>
	<description>A better world through data.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike P. Sinn</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63071</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 04:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63071</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Do you how much is spent on sports, cancer research, and neuroscience research worldwide each year?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you how much is spent on sports, cancer research, and neuroscience research worldwide each year?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: C Ry</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63070</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[C Ry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63070</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Its totally preposterous to compare the total spending by ALL governments on warfare to spending on other things by just the United States or US institutions.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Its totally preposterous to compare the total spending by ALL governments on warfare to spending on other things by just the United States or US institutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mike P. Sinn</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63069</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike P. Sinn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63069</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is an insightful comment.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is an insightful comment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Bob Butterfield</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63068</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bob Butterfield]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63068</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks, @disqus_klOcOYRse8:disqus!  That means a lot to me.   There are a lot of great people like you out there.  Someday, we&#039;ll fix this screwed up world.  I promise.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks, @disqus_klOcOYRse8:disqus!  That means a lot to me.   There are a lot of great people like you out there.  Someday, we&#8217;ll fix this screwed up world.  I promise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Christian</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63067</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 06:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I can just tell by the vocabulary you use that you are far more intelligent then me. Honestly though everything you have said on this webpage is exactly how I feel. I have always known there are other people out there that feel the same way as me, but still finding someone willing to speak out about it is something I am not accustomed to. I&#039;ll be honest when I say at first I figured your page was to good to be true and you were probably going to ask for a donation to some ridiculous fund or political party. But your doing a good thing with this page, and your ideas and the way you present information in an unbiased manner truly earn my respect. I know I&#039;m only one person but for what its worth great job man, it might even be a hopeless fight but when you look back at your life even if you can&#039;t change the system at least you can say to yourself I tried to help in the best way possible.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can just tell by the vocabulary you use that you are far more intelligent then me. Honestly though everything you have said on this webpage is exactly how I feel. I have always known there are other people out there that feel the same way as me, but still finding someone willing to speak out about it is something I am not accustomed to. I&#8217;ll be honest when I say at first I figured your page was to good to be true and you were probably going to ask for a donation to some ridiculous fund or political party. But your doing a good thing with this page, and your ideas and the way you present information in an unbiased manner truly earn my respect. I know I&#8217;m only one person but for what its worth great job man, it might even be a hopeless fight but when you look back at your life even if you can&#8217;t change the system at least you can say to yourself I tried to help in the best way possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Bob Butterfield</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63066</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bob Butterfield]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 01:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63066</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Interesting point, @google-5595aeaba3cb33f5ae531999a67fd170:disqus ! :D]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting point, @google-5595aeaba3cb33f5ae531999a67fd170:disqus ! 😀</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Megan Brooks</title>
		<link>/military/military-spending/#comment-63065</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Brooks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 01:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8255#comment-63065</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#039;t think I can help with that. I can suggest something about the problem of why &quot;we&quot; &quot;allow&quot; these things to go on. You need look no further than the Internet with its legions of zombie hosts and their &quot;bots&quot; that jam websites, harvest email addresses and passwords, send spam, transmit malware and provide any number of other services for their socially deviant owners. The human race is like that to a considerable extent -- legions of zombie bots, doing their leaders&#039; bidding. Which is to allow and empower what goes on.

So what are you going to do about that -- reason with the bots? Raise their awareness? I am afraid that there are vast hordes of humans out their that have little or no capacity to raise their awareness. With enough effort, you might get some number of them to SAY that they have raised their awareness, but being bots they would just be repeating what you wanted them to say. They can say anything, if you tell them what to say first. It might be possible to reprogram some of the bots. That could be interesting.

I am not saying that there is no way out of this. I am not saying that I know a way out of it either.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t think I can help with that. I can suggest something about the problem of why &#8220;we&#8221; &#8220;allow&#8221; these things to go on. You need look no further than the Internet with its legions of zombie hosts and their &#8220;bots&#8221; that jam websites, harvest email addresses and passwords, send spam, transmit malware and provide any number of other services for their socially deviant owners. The human race is like that to a considerable extent &#8212; legions of zombie bots, doing their leaders&#8217; bidding. Which is to allow and empower what goes on.</p>
<p>So what are you going to do about that &#8212; reason with the bots? Raise their awareness? I am afraid that there are vast hordes of humans out their that have little or no capacity to raise their awareness. With enough effort, you might get some number of them to SAY that they have raised their awareness, but being bots they would just be repeating what you wanted them to say. They can say anything, if you tell them what to say first. It might be possible to reprogram some of the bots. That could be interesting.</p>
<p>I am not saying that there is no way out of this. I am not saying that I know a way out of it either.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
